A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1949
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1949
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.561
This collection consists of 7,200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 2 January 1956.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Contents List
- General Files, 1949
  - "A" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 1)
  - Air Forces 1949 (Box 1)
  - Airport (Milton) 1949 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Office 1949 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board - General 1949 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board - Contingent Fund 1949 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board - Investments 1949 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board - Meetings 1949 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board - Treasurer 1949 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education - General 1949 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education - Printed and Mimeographed Material (two folders: 1949 and 1950[empty]) 1949 (Box 1)
  - Ancient Languages 1949 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1949 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions - "A - L" 1949 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions - "M - Z" 1949 (Box 2)
  - Army - General 1949 (Box 2)
  - Army ROTC - Transportation Corps 1949 (Box 2)
  - Army ROTC - Medical Corps 1949 (Box 2)
  - Art and Architecture 1949 (Box 2)
  - Art Commission 1949 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Colleges 1949 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities 1949 (Box 2)
  - Astronomy 1949 (Box 2)
  - Athletics - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) 1949 (Box 2)
  - Athletics 1949 (Box 2)
  - Athletics - Commonwealth Day 1949 (Box 2)
  - Attorney General 1949 (Box 2)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1949 (Box 2)
  - "Ba - Bl" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 2)
  - "Bm - Bz" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 3)
  - Biology - General 1949 (Box 3)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1949 (Box 3)
  - Biology - Blandy Farm 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - General 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Chemistry 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Emergency Housing 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Emergency Housing, Copeley Hill - Activities 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Educational Building, T.A.B. 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Federal Public Housing Authority 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Hospital 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Law Department 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Roads 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Sewage Disposal 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Telephone System 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Water 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings Program - General 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings Program - Architects and Engineers 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings Program - Cabell Hall 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings Program - Chemistry 1949 (Box 3)
  - Buildings Program - Contracts 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Convalescent Children's Home 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Engineering 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Geological Survey Building (see also University Press Building file) 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Law Department 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Life Science Building 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Medical Building 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Men's Dormitories 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Natural Resources Building 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Naval Armory 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Physics 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Power Plant and Heating Mains 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Shops 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Site Plans 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings Program - Student Activities Building 1949 (Box 5)
  - Buildings Program - Student Union 1949 (Box 5)
  - Buildings Program - University Press 1949 (Box 5)
  - Buildings Program - Women's Dormitories 1949 (Box 5)
  - Bursar's Office 1949 (Box 5)
  - Senator Byrd 1949 (Box 5)
  - "C - Ch" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 5)
  - "Ci - Cz" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 5)
  - Carnegie Corporation 1949 (Box 5)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace 1949 (Box 5)
  - Cabell Hall Committee 1949 (Box 5)
  - Catalogue 1949 (Box 5)
  - Cavalier Daily 1949 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry 1949 (Box 5)
  - Commerce and Economics 1949 (Box 5)
  - Committees - Academic Legislation 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Administrative 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Board Committees 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Bookstore (Cooperative) 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Calendar 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Chapel 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Chaperones 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Dean of Students Office Interim Committee 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Draft Deferment Committee for ROTC Students 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Faculty Student 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Gardens 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Graduate 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Hospital Executive Committee 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Institute of Public Affairs Advisory 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Inter-Departmental Committee on Combined Degrees 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Liberal Arts 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Library 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Medical School Building Committee 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Miscellaneous Committees 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Patent Policy 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Processions 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Public Occasions 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Publications 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Radio 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Research 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Rooms on Lawn and Ranges, Committee to Formulate Policy 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Student Union 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Seal, University 1949 (Box 6)
  - Committees - Trees (University) 1949 (Box 6)
  - Commons 1949 (Box 6)
  - Comptroller 1949 (Box 6)
  - Convocation 1949 (Box 6)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 6)
  - Darden, Mr. and Mrs. 1949 (Box 6)
  - Dean Ferguson 1949 (Box 6)
  - Dean Hollingsworth 1949 (Box 6)
  - Assistant Dean's Office 1949 (Box 6)
  - Dean Lewis 1949 (Box 6)
  - Dean Newman 1949 (Box 7)
  - Development Fund 1949 (Box 7)
  - Combined Degrees 1949 (Box 7)
  - Degree Requirements in Other Colleges 1949 (Box 7)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 7)
  - Education - General 1949 (Box 7)
  - Graduate Education 1949 (Box 7)
  - Nursing Education 1949 (Box 7)
  - Engineering 1949 (Box 8)
  - English (two folders: 1949, 1951) 1949 (Box 8)
  - Extension Division 1949 (Box 8)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 8)
  - Faculty 1949 (Box 8)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 8)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Bayly-Tiffany Scholarships 1949 (Box 8)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes Scholarships 1949 (Box 8)
  - Finals 1949 (Box 8)
  - Fletcher, R. R. 1949 (Box 9)
  - Forestry 1949 (Box 9)
  - Forestry - Seward Forest 1949 (Box 9)
  - Foreign Affairs, School of 1949 (Box 9)
  - Forms and Form Letters 1949 (Box 9)
  - Founder's Day 1949 (Box 9)
  - Fraternities 1949 (Box 9)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 9)
  - Garden Club 1949 (Box 9)
  - General Education Board 1949 (Box 9)
  - Geography 1949 (Box 9)
  - Geology 1949 (Box 9)
  - Geological Survey 1949 (Box 9)
  - Germanic Languages 1949 (Box 9)
  - Gifts to the University 1949 (Box 9)
  - Governor's Office 1949 (Box 9)
  - Graduate Department 1949 (Box 9)
  - "Ha - He" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 9)
  - "Hf - Hz" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 9)
  - History 1949 (Box 10)
  - History Commission - World War II 1949 (Box 10)
  - Honor System 1949 (Box 10)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 10)
  - India Conference 1949 (Box 10)
  - Institute of International Education 1949 (Box 10)
  - Institute of Public Affairs 1949 (Box 10)
  - Insurance 1949 (Box 10)
  - Hildreth, W. S. 1949 (Box 10)
  - Housing 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "A" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "B" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "C" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "D" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "E" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "F" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "G" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "H" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "I" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "J" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "J" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "K" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "L" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "M" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "N" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "O" 1949 (Box 10)
  - Invitations - "P" 1949 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "Q" 1949 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "R" 1949 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "S" 1949 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "T" 1949 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "U" 1949 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "V" 1949 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "W" 1949 (Box 11)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1949 (Box 11)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 11)
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1949 (Box 11)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 11)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 11)
  - Legal Papers (W. A. Perkins, Attorney) 1949 (Box 11)
  - Library 1949 (Box 11)
  - Library - Board of Alderman 1949 (Box 11)
  - Library - McGregor Library 1949 (Box 12)
  - Law Department 1949 (Box 12)
  - Lectures - General 1949 (Box 12)
  - Lectures - Page-Barbour 1949 (Box 12)
  - Lectures - Richard 1949 (Box 12)
  - Loan Funds 1949 (Box 12)
  - Madison Hall 1949 (Box 12)
  - Mathematics 1949 (Box 12)
  - Mary Washington College 1949 (Box 12)
  - McIntire Fund 1949 (Box 12)
  - Medical Department 1949 (Box 13)
  - Medical Department - Student Health 1949 (Box 13)
  - Medical Department - Hospital 1949 (Box 13)
  - Military - Miscellaneous (see also Army, Navy, Marine Corps, etc.) 1949 (Box 13)
  - Music 1949 (Box 13)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 13)
  - National Association of State Universities 1949 (Box 13)
  - National Education Association 1949 (Box 13)
  - Naval ROTC 1949 (Box 13)
  - Navy - General 1949 (Box 13)
  - Newcomb, J. L. 1949 (Box 13)
  - Nursing School 1949 (Box 13)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 13)
  - Oak Ridge 1949 (Box 13)
  - "P" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 13)
  - Personnel 1949 (Box 13)
  - Personnel and Placement Office 1949 (Box 13)
  - Philadelphia 1949 (Box 13)
  - Philosophy 1949 (Box 13)
  - Physics 1949 (Box 13)
  - Political Science 1949 (Box 14)
  - Printing 1949 (Box 14)
  - Psychology 1949 (Box 14)
  - Purchase and Printing (State Office) 1949 (Box 14)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 14)
  - Questionnaires 1949 (Box 14)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 14)
  - Radio WUVA 1949 (Box 14)
  - Recommendation - Letters of 1949 (Box 14)
  - Regional Education 1949 (Box 14)
  - Registration 1949 (Box 14)
  - Religion 1949 (Box 14)
  - Requisitions 1949 (Box 14)
  - Research - General 1949 (Box 14)
  - Research - Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1949 (Box 14)
  - Research - Bureau of Public Administration 1949 (Box 14)
  - Research - League of Virginia Counties 1949 (Box 14)
  - Research - Geographical Research Institute 1949 (Box 14)
  - Research - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1949 (Box 14)
  - Research - Medical Research 1949 (Box 14)
  - Research - National Research Council 1949 (Box 14)
  - Research - Naval Research 1949 (Box 15)
  - Richmond Area University Center 1949 (Box 15)
  - Romance Languages 1949 (Box 15)
  - Rural Social Economics 1949 (Box 15)
  - "S" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 15)
  - Senate (University) 1949 (Box 15)
  - Sigma Xi 1949 (Box 15)
  - Sociology 1949 (Box 15)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1949 (Box 15)
  - Speech and Drama 1949 (Box 15)
  - Speeches and Articles 1949 (Box 15)
  - State Board of Education 1949 (Box 15)
  - State Department of Health 1949 (Box 15)
  - Statistics 1949 (Box 15)
  - Student Affairs 1949 (Box 15)
  - Sullivan Award 1949 (Box 15)
  - Summer Session 1949 (Box 15)
  - Surplus Property 1949 (Box 15)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 15)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 16)
  - University News Service 1949 (Box 16)
  - University Press 1949 (Box 16)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 16)
  - Veterans 1949 (Box 16)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1949 (Box 16)
  - Virginia Education Association 1949 (Box 16)
  - Virginia Music Festival 1949 (Box 16)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1949 (Box 16)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1949 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Board Correspondence 1949 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Dockets 1949 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Mr. Anderson 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Judge Barksdale 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mr. Black 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Calcott 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mr. Carrington 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mr. Garnett 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mr. Gay 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mr. Howard 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mr. Mears 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mr. G. Tyler Miller 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Smith 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mr. Stettinius 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mr. Talbott 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Dr. Trout 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Wailes 1949 (Box 17)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Willis 1949 (Box 17)
  - "W" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 18)
  - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Foundation 1949 (Box 18)
  - "X - Y - Z" Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 18)